Now, let's go ahead and style our Udacity Stepper component,
现在我们将对优达学城步进器组件设置样式
which is this component right here.
也就是这个组件
This one's actually pretty fun because if you'll notice,
这个组件比较有意思
on the final version, again,
因为在最终版上
as we've talked about the iOS version is very different
正如之前提到的
than the Android version so what we want to do
iOS 版本与 Android 版本截然不同
is we want to get these things positioned in
我们希望将这些内容横向排列
a row and then what we want to do is just style the buttons a little bit differently.
然后对按钮设置不同的样式
Let's head over to our Udacity Steppers component,
转到 UdaciSteppers 组件
and we need to go ahead and imports the style sheet as well as platform and then,
我们需要导入 StyleSheet 以及 Platform
as I just barely talked about what we want to do,
正如之前提到的
is we want to make sure that these items are displayed in a row rather than vertically.
我们希望确保这些项目横向显示 而不是垂直显示
Eventually, what we'll have is we will have
最终 我们将针对 iOS 和 Android
different buttons for iOS and different buttons for Android.
显示不同的按钮
Let's go ahead and just worry about the iOS versions for now.
暂时先设置 iOS 版按钮
What we can do, as always,
和往常一样
is we can say styles is going to be whatever gets
将 styles 设为
returned from StyleSheet.create and first,
StyleSheet.create 返回的内容
let's create our row property.
首先创建 row 属性
So, flexDirection to row,
输入 flexDirection: ‘row’
so now the main access is going to be
现在主轴将为水平方向
horizontally say flex: 1 as always and then align items center.
输入 flex: 1 然后输入 alignItems: ‘center’
We are going to align the items vertically along the center.
我们将垂直居中排列内容
What we want to do is up here,
转到这里
we want to say style is going to be say styles.row and then what we
将 style 设为 styles.row
also want to do is we also want to say justifyContent space-between.
还将 justifyContent 设为 space-between.
What's happening here, if this is a row,
这行代码的作用是
so the main axis is horizontal,
如果是 row 则主轴是水平方向
then justify content is going to align everything horizontally
所有内容都水平对齐
spaced out with space evenly between the items and then now,
各项内容之间存在间隔
what we can do here,
在这里
is we'll just do an inline style and we will
设置内嵌样式
say flexDirection is going to be row as well,
输入 flexDirection: ‘row’
but without all of the stuff on it.
但是没有这些设置
Now, if we just save that, you'll notice,
保存下代码
let's refresh Android, you'll notice that things
刷新下 Android 应用
are aligned horizontally now which is good.
你会发现内容水平对齐 很不错
Next, let's go ahead and make our iosBtn style,
接着设置 iOS 按钮样式
so we'll come down here and we'll say iosBtn.
输入 iosBtn
If you remember what it's going to look like is this right here.
最终界面是这样的
We will say the background is going to be white,
将 background 设为 white
and let's go ahead and import that real quick.
快速导入 white
Eventually, we're going to need a few other colors as well,
最终 我们还将需要其他颜色
so I'll do that right now.
所以我现在就导入这些颜色
Just gray and purple,
导入 gray 和 purple
backgroundColor is going to be a white,
backgroundColor 设为 white
borderColor is going to be purple,
borderColor 设为 purple
borderWidth is going to be one,
borderWidth 设为 1
borderRadius, let's go ahead and set that to let's say three.
borderRadius 设为 3
We'll give it a padding of five,
padding 设为 5
and a paddingLeft of 25 as well as a paddingRight of 25.
paddingLeft 和 paddingRight 都设为 25
Now, let's apply our iosBtn to both of these touchable components right here.
现在将 iosBtn 应用到这里的两个可触摸组件上
Right here, we will say style and
输入 style
style.iosBtn and then we will
然后输入 styles.iosBtn
do the exact same thing for this touchable component right here.
然后对这里的可触摸组件执行完全一样的操作
Now, let's take a look at what this looks like.
现在看看应用界面
We're getting there, it's a little bit closer,
离最终效果越来越近了
you'll notice that right down the middle here,
你会发现 在中间
we still have that borderRadius.
依然存在 borderRadius
What we want to do is we want to make these flat rather than having a borderRadius.
我们希望这些是扁平的 而不是具有 borderRadius
What we can do is,
我们向第一个组件
let's go ahead and pass an array to this first one.
传入一个数组
We want to apply all of these styles,
我们希望应用所有这些样式
but we also want to come in here and we will say
但是我们还希望
borderTopRightRadius is going to be
将 borderTopRightRadius 设为 0
zero and borderBottomRightRadius is also going to be zero.
将 borderBottomRightRadius 也设为 0
Now, if we look at our app,
现在看看应用界面
you'll notice right here,
你会发现这里是扁平的
that's flat as well as on the bottom and then we want to do the same thing down here.
底部也是扁平的 然后在下面进行相同的设置
This will be an array and then we want to say on this one borderTopLeftRadius is zero,
这将是一个数组 然后将 borderTopLeftRadius 设为 0
and borderBottomLeftRadius is also going to be zero,
borderBottomLeftRadius 也设为 0
which should flatten those out a bit.
这些将稍微扁平化了
I'm not sure whether it is bleeding right here.
不确定这里是否出现 bleeding 情况
It looks like it's a bug with React Native.
似乎这是 React Native 的 bug
When I built this for production and the other version of the app, I didn't have that.
当我构建应用正式版和其他版本时 没有出现这种情况
I think it should be fine to not worry about that for right now.
我觉得暂时不用管这个
This looks pretty good as far as the iOS buttons are concerned.
对于 iOS 按钮来说 看起来很不错了
Instead of using black, here,
这里不再设为 black
let's go ahead and iOS,
在 iOS 上
or at least on this button, we'll use purple,
或者至少在这个按钮上 我们将使用紫色
and then down here let's have purple as well.
这里也设为 purple
All right. That looks great.
看起来不错
Before we jump into styling for Android,
在为 Android 版设置样式之前
let's go ahead and style our metrics right here.
我们为这些指标设置样式
What we can do is,
转到这里
let's say this one is going to have,
输入 metricCounter
we'll call it metricCounter and what that's going to have say width is going to be 85,
将 width 设为 85
then we want to justify everything on the center using justifyContent and alignItems.
然后使用 justifyContent 和 alignItems 让一切居中
Then now, let's go ahead and add some inline styles to the text components.
现在向 Text 组件添加一些内嵌样式
Let's say font size of 24 on this one with textAlign center.
将 fontSize 设为 24 textAlign 设为 center
On this one, all we will say is font size of 18 so it's a little bit smaller,
对于这个 Text 将 fontSize 设为 18 字号要小些
and the color instead of being black is going to be gray.
颜色将为灰色 而不是黑色
Now, let's see what that looks like.
看看应用效果
That looks pretty good.
看起来不错
Now, let's go ahead and style our Android buttons real quick.
现在快速地设置 Android 按钮样式
Down here, let's create a new property.
在下面新建一个属性
We'll call it an androidBtn.
称之为 androidBtn
What this is going to have?
它将比 iOS 简单很多
It's going to be a lot simpler than the iOS one will just say margin of five.
将 margin 设为 5
The backgroundColor is going to be purple,
backgroundColor 设为 purple
give it some padding of 10 and then a borderRadius of two.
padding 设为 10 borderRadius 设为 2
Now, what we need to do is depending on what platform we're on,
现在 我们将根据所在的平台
that's what style we need to apply.
应用样式
Up here, let's say,
在这里
if the platform is iOS,
如果平台为 iOS
then what we want to do is render these components,
则渲染这些组件
we fix the formatting here and then if it's not on iOS,
调整下格式 如果不是 iOS
just copy and paste this, render these components.
复制粘贴这些 渲染这些组件
We do need to make some changes real quick.
我们需要快速修改下
You'll notice if we look at the final version,
看看最终版界面
these icons are actually a little bit thinner than these ones over here.
发现这些图标的边框比这些图标的要细一些
The reason for that is because we are using a different component library.
原因是我们使用的是不同的组件库
We'll say, if we're on iOS,
如果我们位于 iOS 上
instead of rendering FontAwesome icons.
则渲染这些 Entypo 图标
Let's go ahead and render these Entypo ones.
而不是 FontAwesome 图标
We can still use minus and plus,
依然可以使用加减号
still use the same sizes.
尺寸不变
Then now, down here FontAwesome works for Android,
在下面 FontAwesome 适用于 Android
but instead of iOS,
将这里的 iOS
we will say render our androidBtn styles.
改为 androidBtn 样式
We have an error on line 36.
第 36 行有个错误
It's because we're missing a curly brace right there.
因为这里丢了花括号
That's because we're missing a curly brace right there.
这是因为这里丢了花括号
All right, this looks good.
看起来正常了
You'll notice on Android R, the color of our icons are purple.
在 Android 上 图标颜色是紫色
We do not want that.
我们不希望使用紫色
We want them to be white.
而是使用白色
We can say it is down here,
在这里
it's going to be whites.
设为 white
There we go, we now have our Android styles over here and our iOS styles over here.
好了 这是 Android 样式 这是 iOS 样式